Guide to the Chon A. Noriega Revelaciones/Revelations, Hispanic art of evanescence: exhibition sponsored by the Hispanic American Studies Program at, 1993 Nov. 6-Dec. 19
Department of Special Collections
Noriega, Chon A., 1961-, collector. Revelaciones/Revelations, Hispanic art of evanescence: exhibition sponsored by the Hispanic American Studies Program at,
1993 Nov. 6-Dec. 19
M0696
Noriega, Chon A., 1961-, collector.
8 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection includes files, catalog, press coverage, 68 slides, raw video coverage, one finished video, an audio cassette, clippings, and publications relating to the Revelaciones/Revelations exhibit.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Audiovisual materials require two weeks advance notice before use to allow staff time to have use copies made.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1994, with an addition in 1996.
Biography
Chon Noriega and José Piedra curated the exhibit Revelaciones/Revelations, Hispanic art of evanescence, which was sponsored by the Hispanic American Studies Program at Cornell University and the Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art, at Cornell University between 1993 Nov. 6-Dec. 19.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Includes files, catalog, press coverage, 68 slides, raw video coverage, one finished video, an audio cassette, clippings, and publications.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Brito Avellana, Maria.; Cardillo, Rimer.; Gonzâalez, Ronald.;. 00$aGronk.; Martinez, Daniel J.; Mesa-Bains, Amalia.; Ortiz, Raphael Montanez.; Osorio, Pepâon.; Munoz, Celia Alvarez, 1931-; Piedra, Josâe.; Cornell University. Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art.; Cornell University. Hispanic American Studies Program.; Mexican American art.; Phonotapes.; Slides.; Video recordings.; Video tapes.
Collection Contents
- Series 1. Publications
  - Revelaciones / Revelations: hispanic art of evanescence - press clippings (Box 1)
  - Revelaciones / Revelations: slides, 68 slides; 35 mm. (Box 1)
  - Cornell Magazine, pg. 111994, Accession 1994-187 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - On the Wall, pg. 15 (re. Daniel J. Martinez)1993-1994, Accession 1994-187 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Art in America, pg. 25 (re. Daniel J. Martinez)1994, Accession 1994-187 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - La Voz: articles by Jose Piedra, David Alonzo, Mary Fagot, et al. No paging, section marked with bookmarks1994, Accession 1994-187 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Jose Piedra's files on the aftermath of exhibit, including analyses of the protest, copies1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper coverage, 10/25/93-11/20/931993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 10)
  - Newspaper coverage, 11/21/93-2/6/941993-1994, Accession 1994-187 (Box 11)
  - The Cornell Daily Sun1993 Nov. 22, 23, 24; 1993 Dec. 3 (Box 2)
  - A visitor's guide to Revelaciones / Revelations - hispanic art of evanescence, 1 pamphlet (4 copies) (Box 2)
  - Cornell Chronicle1993 Oct. 28 & 1993 Nov. 4 (Box 2)
  - The Greek Globe. -- Rush ed. 19941993 Dec. 1 (Box 2)
  - La lucha: the voice of the Latino struggle1993 Dec. (Box 2)
  - Ithaca Times1993 Nov. 11; 1993 Nov. 24 (Box 2)
  - The Voice: a forum for women's empowerment. -- Premier issue, vol. 1, 1994 Feb. (Box 2)
  - The Cornell Review, 1993 Nov. 29 (Box 2)
  - The Ithaca Journal, 1993 Nov. 4 (Box 2)
  - The Ithaca Journal, 1993 Nov. 18, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - The Ithaca Journal, 1993 Nov. 19 (Box 2)
  - The Ithaca Journal, 1993 Nov. 20, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - The Ithaca Journal, 1993 Nov. 22 (Box 2)
  - The Ithaca Journal, 1993 Nov. 24 (Box 2)
  - The Cornell American, 1993 Nov. (Box 2)
  - Folder of miscellaneous photocopies of articles from various newspapers (Box 2)
  - 1 loosely bound folder of published articles of Revelaciones / Revelations. (Box 2)
    Includes advertising poster.
- Series 2. Audiovisual materials
  Audiovisual materials require two weeks advance notice before use to allow staff time to have use copies made.
  - Revelaciones = Revelations: Hispanic Arts of Revelations, 1 videotape: VHS (Box 3)
  - Revelaciones = Revelations: Hispanic Arts of Revelations, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 3)
  - Offline. Episode 10, 1 videotape: VHS (Box 3)
  - Tapes 1 & 2, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 3)
  - Tapes 3 & 4, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 3)
  - Tapes 5 & 6, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 3)
  - Tapes 8 & 12, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 3)
  - Tapes 9 & 10, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 3)
  - Tapes 11 & 15, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 3)
  - Tapes 16 & 26, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 4)
  - Tapes 18, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 4)
  - Tapes 19, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 4)
  - Tapes 20, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 4)
  - Tapes 21, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 4)
  - Tapes 22, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 4)
  - Tapes 24, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 4)
  - Tapes 26, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 4)
  - Tapes 27, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 5)
  - Tapes 29, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 5)
  - Tapes 28 & 29, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 5)
  - Tapes 17 & 23, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 5)
  - Tapes 17 & 23, 2 videotapes: VHS (Box 5)
  - Cornell - Rafael, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 5)
  - Cornell - Rafael, 1 videotape: VHS (Box 5)
  - Latino sit-in, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 5)
  - Latino sit-in, 1 videotape: VHS (Box 5)
  - Background interviews / Gronk & Ronald Gonzalez, 1 videotape: U-matic (Box 5)
  - Background interviews / Gronk & Ronald Gonzalez, 2 videotapes: VHS (Box 5)
  - Artists roundtable, 2 videotapes: VHS (Box 5)
  - Critics symposium 1, 2 videotapes: VHS (Box 5)
  - Critics symposium 2, 2 videotapes: VHS (Box 5)
  - Cassette tape: for installation of Ronald Gonzalez materials, mixed by James Spano, 1993, Accession 1994-187; 1 audiotape (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series 3. Press clippings
  - Press clippings in binder, Accession 1996-200 (Box 6)
- Series 4. Exhibit files
  - Correspondence about exhibit1993-1994, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence about exhibit1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence about exhibit1992-1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correpondence, general1992-1994, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Critics (exhibit)1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Dia de los Muertos1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Dismantling of exhibit, funding1993-1994, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Liabilities/agreements1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Mailing list1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Materials/purchases1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Materials/purchases1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Materials/purchases1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Meals1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Series 5. Subject files on artists
  - Brito, Maria1993-1994, Accession 1994-187 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Cardillo, Rimer1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Gonzalez, Ronald1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Gronk1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Martinez, Daniel J.1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Mesa-Bains, Amalia1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Munoz, Celia Alvarez1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Ortiz, Raphael Montanez1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Ortiz, Raphael Montanez (Book trials)1993, Accession 1994-187 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Velez, Edin1993-1994, Accession 1994-187 (Box 8, Folder 10)